Hello

I'm Williams Alex

Full-Stack Software Engineer

+234 7012714644

williamsalexjr@gmail.com

Github link

Linkedin

Bio

I'm a Software engineer with over 5 years of working experience.

I derive joy in performing my duties with the technologies I've used throughout my working experience.

I also love to learn new technologies and expand my knowledge as a software engineer.

Solving problems and creating new ideas and inventions is like an everyday task for me, it keeps me going.

Experience

Mar 2023 - Present · | Uburu Health · Full-time

Software Engineer

Made modifications and upgraded the company's website/application.

Jan 2024 - Oct 2024 | Erudyte · Contract

Software Engineer

Added new features to the company's application.

Jul 2021 - Present | Intelligent Innovations Co. · Full-time

Software Engineer

- 1. Built the company's website using Next js.
- 2. Built various email templates using vanilla Html and Css technologies.
- 3. Built an e-learning or edu tech platform using both Nuxt js and Next/Nx, you can learn various skills from this platform, for more head on to https://skillpaddy.com
- 4. Made modifications and upgraded a financial platform where you can basically apply for loans.

5. Modified and built a job application platform, this forum allows users to be able to apply and create jobs.

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022 | Mega Beauty · Contract

Software Engineer

- 1. Built a full stack application that allows users to be able to conduct voting actions for beauty contests.
- 2. Learnt and wrote unit test for the application, i wrote the test using jest.
- 3. Deployed the application on both development and production environments.

Feb 2020 - May 2021 · | Diamond Acre Software · Full-time

Software Engineer

- 1. Created user interface for the companies website, the technologies used were vanilla Html5, Css3 and JavaScript.
- 2. Created mobile interfaces which used Vue.js and Quiser library to render its UI as a cross platform mobile application.
- 3. Made modifications to one of the company's big products using React js. 4. Created a full stack quiz application, the technologies used was Vue, the Quiser library, Node js/Express framework and MongoDB database Learned about Nginx technology.

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020 · Green Mouse Technologies · Full-time

Software Engineer and Tutor

- 1. Created user interfaces for various websites/applications with technologies like Html5, Css3, Javascript and Bootstrap.
- 2. Made more use of CSS3 animations and transitions on the some of the company's application
- 3. Created mock ups for the company's products.
- 4. Learnt a bit of PHP
- 5. Tutored students who needed to learn about web development and tech in general

Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, Next, Nuxt, Node/Express, MongoDB, Unit Testing (Jest)

Education

2017

Gateway polytechnic Saapade, Ogun State Nigeria. HND, Computer Science.